/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603691a30c817f0398fac0ae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-various-career-options-after-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Well, there are many many options for an engineer after BE/B Tech. An engineer to be placed in a good company should have the basic ideas in some of the subjects (with some practical exposure). That apart, you can even choose a handful of them to master the concept. Plenty of job opportunities are surely available. Please do not directly think of joining good companies. With some experience in small or medium industries, things are going to be better. Do not worry much about your 'initial' salary. Let it be any kind of job, put in continuous and undaunted efforts. And treat that as a 'training period\", and \"investment\". In your engineering there will be major groups/areas. You decide that in which area you want to concentrate and work. You will have to learn a lot in that area. Be a performer Continue Reading Well, there are many many options for an engineer after BE/B Tech. An engineer to be placed in a good company should have the basic ideas in some of the subjects (with some practical exposure). That apart, you can even choose a handful of them to master the concept. Plenty of job opportunities are surely available. Please do not directly think of joining good companies. With some experience in small or medium industries, things are going to be better. Do not worry much about your 'initial' salary. Let it be any kind of job, put in continuous and undaunted efforts. And treat that as a 'training period\", and \"investment\". In your engineering there will be major groups/areas. You decide that in which area you want to concentrate and work. You will have to learn a lot in that area. Be a performer Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:49:23.591Z"),
    "question" : "What are the various career options after engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603691e60c817f0398fac176"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-career-options-in-construction-domain-after-graduation-in-electrical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "I had addressed this topic in my answer to the following question. I am an ECE 3rd year student. How can I understand the job market for ECE students?                  Below is the copy of that answer with few modifications.                     I have given some information about job opportunities for ECE students. This may not  cover all the areas. Also if any one finds any error in this post and  need any clarifications, write a comment. I will take the input and modify the post. Expecting more suggestion from Industry experts.           Whenever I meet an ECE student and ask him why you took  ECE, most of the time I get the same answer, \"I can go to Core job or IT job\". When I started to discuss with them, then only I understood that most of the ECE students did not understand the Core job Continue Reading I had addressed this topic in my answer to the following question. I am an ECE 3rd year student. How can I understand the job market for ECE students?                  Below is the copy of that answer with few modifications.                     I have given some information about job opportunities for ECE students. This may not  cover all the areas. Also if any one finds any error in this post and  need any clarifications, write a comment. I will take the input and modify the post. Expecting more suggestion from Industry experts.           Whenever I meet an ECE student and ask him why you took  ECE, most of the time I get the same answer, \"I can go to Core job or IT job\". When I started to discuss with them, then only I understood that most of the ECE students did not understand the Core job Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:50:30.494Z"),
    "question" : "What are career options in construction domain after graduation in electrical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603692700c817f0398fac2f4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-career-options-for-a-mechanical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Mechanical Engineering is a vast field. Being said that getting quality job as a mechanical engineer in India is difficult task as our Manufacturing Industry does not have a growth that our service Industries have. Below are different career options for Mechanical engineering pass out. ESE : UPSC conducts Engineering services examination every year. Best opportunity ME Engineer can get in Govt. Sector. (Not all posts are that good)PSU Jobs : Public Sector Undertaking Companies like ONGC, IOCL, BPCL, HPCL, GAIL, BHEL, BEL, SAIL ..etc are main employer for ME Engineers with good pay and perks.Research Organisations: If you are more leaned towards research job opt for ISRO or DRDO.PVT Sector Jobs: L&T, Automobile companies like Mahindra, TVS, Hero Motocrp, TATA Motors ..etc are next biggest empContinue Reading Continue Reading Tony Scaria",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:52:48.720Z"),
    "question" : "What are some career options for a mechanical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603692930c817f0398fac37d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-civil-engineering-a-good-career-choice?-",
    "answer" : "Akshay Bangad Yes.Civil engineering is oldest branch of engineering. Entire civilization (सभ्यता ) is related to this branch and thus it has got the name CIVIL Engineering. But one always forgets that it is “civil engineering” rather than BUILDING ENGINEERING. So I would mention some works where civil engineers are required. In building and construction of houses, industries, commercial structures etc which is commonly known to all.In all the geological and geotechnical investigation and site selection for all the mega projects of DAMS, channels and other hydraulic projects.There are N numbers of surveys and planning of cities , townships there you need themExecution of construction of roads,railways, airport runways etc.Bridges, tunnels ,decks etc are some places where you are 0 without civil engineers.SContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:53:23.089Z"),
    "question" : "Is civil engineering a good career choice? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603692dd0c817f0398fac445"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-of-civil-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the scope of civil engineering?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:54:37.911Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope of civil engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603692ff0c817f0398fac4d1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-can-I-ultimately-do-with-an-engineering-degree?-",
    "answer" : "In todays day and age? No. absolutely not, it is probably one of the worst, I’m compairing professions which requires the same amount of effort and length of education. For example lawyers, dentist, doctors, economists etc. Engineers earn basically the same amount as any profession with no university degree required. Engineer is not a trademark, like a plumber. So anyone can work as an engineer. As an engineer you are totally dependent on a handfull of employers, not good for future income boosts. If you as an engineer would, through some ground breaking innovation, save the worlds energy problems you wouldn’t get rich. because that was expected of you. But the CEO would get rich and the managers underneath for producing good results, but you as an engineer, probably some mediocare watch a Continue Reading In todays day and age? No. absolutely not, it is probably one of the worst, I’m compairing professions which requires the same amount of effort and length of education. For example lawyers, dentist, doctors, economists etc. Engineers earn basically the same amount as any profession with no university degree required. Engineer is not a trademark, like a plumber. So anyone can work as an engineer. As an engineer you are totally dependent on a handfull of employers, not good for future income boosts. If you as an engineer would, through some ground breaking innovation, save the worlds energy problems you wouldn’t get rich. because that was expected of you. But the CEO would get rich and the managers underneath for producing good results, but you as an engineer, probably some mediocare watch a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:55:11.886Z"),
    "question" : "What can I ultimately do with an engineering degree? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036931c0c817f0398fac4f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-becoming-a-software-engineer-worth-it?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is becoming a software engineer worth it?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:55:40.331Z"),
    "question" : "Is becoming a software engineer worth it? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036935b0c817f0398fac5af"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-do-software-engineers-make-so-much?-With-so-many-students-pursuing-careers-in-software-engineering-today,-do-you-see-salaries-going-down-significantly-in-the-future?-If-so,-by-how-much?-",
    "answer" : "Why Software Engineers make so much?    I am myself a software engineer working in India. And confidently say that pay for software engineers here in India who work for global companies are quite competitive among same grade of companies  and above compared to other sectors.      Software engineering job is unique (don't shoot me, keep calm and read further ) and it is quite similar to any other creative or artistic job, say for example a diamond cutter or pottery making job. A potter makes his piece one at a time, one person at a time. Now if you want to make another pot you need exact same person exact same time or more time depending on his mood. Software writing also same, only for very first time. Trick of Software is, it is  entirely different when you want to make one more copy of Continue Reading Why Software Engineers make so much?    I am myself a software engineer working in India. And confidently say that pay for software engineers here in India who work for global companies are quite competitive among same grade of companies  and above compared to other sectors.      Software engineering job is unique (don't shoot me, keep calm and read further ) and it is quite similar to any other creative or artistic job, say for example a diamond cutter or pottery making job. A potter makes his piece one at a time, one person at a time. Now if you want to make another pot you need exact same person exact same time or more time depending on his mood. Software writing also same, only for very first time. Trick of Software is, it is  entirely different when you want to make one more copy of Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:56:43.583Z"),
    "question" : "Why do software engineers make so much? With so many students pursuing careers in software engineering today, do you see salaries going down significantly in the future? If so, by how much? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603693800c817f0398fac639"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-chemical-engineering-a-good-branch?-Why-or-why-not?-",
    "answer" : "Q. Is Chemical Engineering a good choice? You are probably asking this, because you have some interest in Chem. Eng, but are not sure whether to invest 4 years of your life into studying the subject? In that case, I will try my best to give an unbiased opinion about Chem Eng. from my experience of studying the subject. Pros: Chem Eng. is a genuinely interesting course to study: If you enjoyed studying Chemistry in 12th grade, then studying Chem Eng. will be an easy and painless task. A lot of the modules are chemistry (organic, physical) and applied chemistry, and there is seriously a lot of interesting material that is covered, specially in the latter years of the course.Decent opportunities in the Indian government sector: A B.Tech in Chem. Eng will open several doors for job opportunities iContinue Reading Q. Is Chemical Engineering a good choice? You are probably asking this, because you have some interest in Chem. Eng, but are not sure whether to invest 4 years of your life into studying the subject? In that case, I will try my best to give an unbiased opinion about Chem Eng. from my experience of studying the subject. Pros: Chem Eng. is a genuinely interesting course to study: If you enjoyed studying Chemistry in 12th grade, then studying Chem Eng. will be an easy and painless task. A lot of the modules are chemistry (organic, physical) and applied chemistry, and there is seriously a lot of interesting material that is covered, specially in the latter years of the course.Decent opportunities in the Indian government sector: A B.Tech in Chem. Eng will open several doors for job opportunities iContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:57:20.093Z"),
    "question" : "Is chemical engineering a good branch? Why or why not? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036939a0c817f0398fac671"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-options-after-graduating-from-chemical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Anish L",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:57:46.899Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career options after graduating from chemical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603693b50c817f0398fac6e9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-common-career-landmines-that-software-engineers-should-watch-out-for?-",
    "answer" : "Kurt Guntheroth Janko Jerinic Working in the wrong industry: I started out in the Test and Measurement industry, an industry with negative long term growth. I would have made more money in a growth industry like software applications. When I had an, um, opportunity to change industries, I targeted growth industries.Getting comfortable doing what you’re doing: It’s easy to settle in and believe that you have found lifetime employment. You become a deep domain expert on your company’s products. The only problem is, most companies don’t last for the full length of your 45–55 year career. If you don’t keep a broad focus, you can find yourself with skills that are so highly specialized that you are unemployable. For instance, I happen to be (or have been) one of the planet’s half dozen top experts on functional test of RAM Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:58:13.050Z"),
    "question" : "What are some common career landmines that software engineers should watch out for? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603693f80c817f0398fac7a1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-biggest-career-mistakes-made-by-engineers?-",
    "answer" : "This answer is written in Indian context The Biggest CAREER mistakes which engineers or engineering freshers are doing is working in SERVICE BASED COMPANIES like TCS,CTS,IBM,Infosys,Accenture,wipro etc etc companies. No engineers must ever work for these companies All these aforementioned companies are not engineering companies.These companies require graduates of any kind ONLY to perform english speaking data entry worksIt is a curse to our country that lakhs of engineering students without doing any proper research are ending up in one of these firms. This is the biggest career mistake of any engineering graduate.These companies Only PERFORM data entry works in age old toolsThese company employees are engineers by degree but by occupation they are only doing the work of a clerk who can speContinue Reading This answer is written in Indian context The Biggest CAREER mistakes which engineers or engineering freshers are doing is working in SERVICE BASED COMPANIES like TCS,CTS,IBM,Infosys,Accenture,wipro etc etc companies. No engineers must ever work for these companies All these aforementioned companies are not engineering companies.These companies require graduates of any kind ONLY to perform english speaking data entry worksIt is a curse to our country that lakhs of engineering students without doing any proper research are ending up in one of these firms. This is the biggest career mistake of any engineering graduate.These companies Only PERFORM data entry works in age old toolsThese company employees are engineers by degree but by occupation they are only doing the work of a clerk who can speContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T17:59:20.133Z"),
    "question" : "What are the biggest career mistakes made by engineers? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603694260c817f0398fac845"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-aeronautical-engineering-as-a-career?-What-are-the-career-options?-",
    "answer" : "Shreyus J Suvarna Aeronautical Engineering Introduction “Aeronautical Engineering” is one of the most popular fields for the students who wish to make their career in aircraft, airplanes, jet planes and space shuttles. Aeronautical engineering is the deep study of “Aeronautics”. Aeronautics term has come from the ancient Greek word “Aer” which means ‘Air’ and “Nautike” which means ‘navigation of the air’. Aeronautics is the art or science of the manufacturing, design, and study of air flight capable machines. “Aeronautical engineering involves the study, design and research of the machines or airplanes which moves in the space and air sphere of the earth”. Aeronautical engineers use their technical knowledge in designing, constructing, maintaining and testing the aircraft and related systems. The field, Aeronautic Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:00:06.438Z"),
    "question" : "How is aeronautical engineering as a career? What are the career options? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603694660c817f0398fac8f5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-type-of-software-engineers-will-never-succeed-in-their-career?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Alpesh Choubisa",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:01:10.189Z"),
    "question" : "What type of software engineers will never succeed in their career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603694900c817f0398fac938"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-future-scope-of-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Aswin S, former Engineer  at Volvo TrucksAnswered 1 year agoWhat is the future scope of mechanical engineering? Aswin S Future is bright…but different I will explain… One thing is there is basically two types of jobs from Indian perspective. One is hardcore industry like steel, petroleum e.t.c mostly.. government organizations.. Second type of jobs are the ones in OEMs in different areas and the suppliers and service provides. Eg Volvo is an automotive OEM and Robert Bosch is a tier 1 supplier who provides different components and services for these OEMs. I work for Volvo and hence my answer will be more aligned towards the second type of jobs.. Now coming to the answer. As I said the scope for both mechanical and electrical.. the oldest engineering branches will always be there as till the end of world. But we have to adapt to modern style of working. The second and most important thing to keep in mind while re Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:01:52.676Z"),
    "question" : "What is the future scope of mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603694c00c817f0398fac9d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-computer-engineering-a-good-career?-",
    "answer" : "Aakash Gupta Well, It can be yes if you are good at the subject and are interested in the field. The sole purpose of the computer engineers is to match the hardware and software for the requirements. They have to test, design the systems and develop the memory devices or processors. All of the systems and physical components are to be properly manufactured and help in the safe and effective running of the digital worlds. Computer engineering is much preferred by the students because of the following reasons: · Multiple job opportunities- since everything being now relied on the technology, computer engineers have a broad and flexible range of job opportunities. Gradutaes with computer engineering have the multiple disciplines to choose from for the jobs like they can go in: robotics, artificial intellige Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:02:40.595Z"),
    "question" : "Is computer engineering a good career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036950b0c817f0398facaa5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-typical-stages-in-the-career-of-a-software-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Kurt Guntheroth Ivan Babak Rookie: 0 years experience. Does what they’re told and tries not to make too many mistakes.New kid: 1–2 years experience. Does what they’re told, and usually doesn’t look too stupid. Sometimes give themselves great airs about how much smarter they are than the more senior staff, but still make rookie mistakes often enough to keep them humble.Journeyman: 2–8 years experience. If they were actually smart, they’ve learned some stuff, and are generally capable of reasonable independence on projects. If they weren’t very smart, they still need a lot of supervision.Unemployed: business downturn.Experienced: 8–15 years experience. Generally capable of reasonable independent work without drama. It is often at this point in a career where burnout becomes a serious possibility. Each developer has a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:03:55.465Z"),
    "question" : "What are the typical stages in the career of a software engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695280c817f0398facb21"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-Electrical-Engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Electrical Engineering is an extremely diverse field, and terming it as the “study of electricity” is a gross oversimplification. We basically attempt to answer some of the following questions, under the specified sub-fields (Each number in each sub-field addresses the same problem from different points of view): Communication: How do we build technologies that enable two humans on opposite ends of the Earth talk to each other with quality matching real life conversation, no delays, and when the two people are themselves moving? How do we make sure that it’s secure and others can’t overhear?How do we scale the above to allow 7 billion people to converse simultaneously, or listen to famous personalities giving speeches, without any interference, loss of data/quality, or overload?How can we enContinue Reading Electrical Engineering is an extremely diverse field, and terming it as the “study of electricity” is a gross oversimplification. We basically attempt to answer some of the following questions, under the specified sub-fields (Each number in each sub-field addresses the same problem from different points of view): Communication: How do we build technologies that enable two humans on opposite ends of the Earth talk to each other with quality matching real life conversation, no delays, and when the two people are themselves moving? How do we make sure that it’s secure and others can’t overhear?How do we scale the above to allow 7 billion people to converse simultaneously, or listen to famous personalities giving speeches, without any interference, loss of data/quality, or overload?How can we enContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:04:24.860Z"),
    "question" : "What is Electrical Engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695500c817f0398facbbb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-best-engineering-fields?-",
    "answer" : "Kumar Anand Branch is not all that important That’s right. Most students and parents seem to be very focused on getting in to the “best” branch (Computer Science, Electronics & Telecommunications, Mechanical, Chemical, Civil, etc.) Everybody wants to get into the “top” branch. Everybody wants to know which branch has the best “scope” in the future. This is misguided. There are a number of reasons why the branch doesn’t matter all that much: If you study in a good college, all branches have “scope”. There are successful businesses and well-paying jobs in all disciplines, including civil engineering, and chemical engineering. And the vast majority of computer science graduates in the country do not have decent jobs (because there are so many of them!) If you study in a bad college, a good branch is not goi Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:05:04.464Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best engineering fields? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695770c817f0398facbf5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-make-career-after-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Vamsidhar Vupmandla ABOUT MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Now-a-days the scope of mechanical engineering is expanding beyond its traditional boundaries and is more of inter-disciplinary in nature. Mechanical engineers are focusing their attention towards new areas such as nanotechnology, development of composite materials, biomedical applications, and environmental conservation. With this shift in paradigm the new job avenues have been opened for the mechanical engineers. Further with the call of Make in India given by Hon’ble PM of India the manufacturing sector shall be empowered and big players are going to setup their manufacturing plants in India. Mechanical engineering is one of the oldest branches of engineering, dating back to when the first wheels were put to practical use by mounting them on an axle to make a Continue Reading ABOUT MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Now-a-days the scope of mechanical engineering is expanding beyond its traditional boundaries and is more of inter-disciplinary in nature. Mechanical engineers are focusing their attention towards new areas such as nanotechnology, development of composite materials, biomedical applications, and environmental conservation. With this shift in paradigm the new job avenues have been opened for the mechanical engineers. Further with the call of Make in India given by Hon’ble PM of India the manufacturing sector shall be empowered and big players are going to setup their manufacturing plants in India. Mechanical engineering is one of the oldest branches of engineering, dating back to when the first wheels were put to practical use by mounting them on an axle to make a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:05:43.727Z"),
    "question" : "How can I make career after mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695a50c817f0398facc8d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-work-of-an-electrical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Electrical engineering is the design, building and maintenance of electrical control systems, machinery and equipment. Some electrical engineering concerns are also found in mechanical and civil engineering. The term electrical engineering often includes electronics engineering. While electrical engineers mainly focus on large-scale production and distribution of electrical power, electronics engineers are concerned with smaller electronic circuits and often also work with computers and other modern technologies. However, any undergraduate course will include elements of both electrical and electronics engineering. Electrical engineers work in transport networks, lighting, heating, ventilation, lift systems, power generation and distribution, renewable energy, manufacturing and construction. Continue Reading Electrical engineering is the design, building and maintenance of electrical control systems, machinery and equipment. Some electrical engineering concerns are also found in mechanical and civil engineering. The term electrical engineering often includes electronics engineering. While electrical engineers mainly focus on large-scale production and distribution of electrical power, electronics engineers are concerned with smaller electronic circuits and often also work with computers and other modern technologies. However, any undergraduate course will include elements of both electrical and electronics engineering. Electrical engineers work in transport networks, lighting, heating, ventilation, lift systems, power generation and distribution, renewable energy, manufacturing and construction. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:06:29.338Z"),
    "question" : "What is the work of an electrical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695b90c817f0398faccb5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-opportunities-for-civil-engineers-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "Priobrata Choudhury Civil engineering has quite a beautiful scope in India. But remember, you will have to be patient. And I can explain why..!! Civil engineering is a branch of engineering which deals with people, civilization of a country, their needs and basic facilities. So as long as there are humans and as long as we have natural phenomenon like earthquakes and tornadoes civil engineers will be required.  Just take an example of a routine life of Mr. Sharma. He wakes up in the morning brushes his teeth, takes showers, has breakfast, goes to office, works over there, has lunch, again works, comes back to home, has fun with family, has lunch, watches TV and then goes to bed. Now in above example, he wants water for his morning activities, it has been indicated that if people do not get morning water supply t Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:06:49.395Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job opportunities for civil engineers in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695d60c817f0398facd30"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-software-engineering-a-good-career-choice?-I-know-it-pays-well-initially,-but-if-you-look-at-the-managing-directors-of-most-companies,-they-are-people-with-MBAs.-",
    "answer" : "First of all, You really need to know that at least 99.9% of ALL software engineers ARE NOT, and I REPEAT they ARE NOT Engineers in ANY way, shape or form! RARE are the architects that do Engineer a software solution and infrastructure! Don’t trust any answer in favor of SW engineering if its coming from a software engineer (I’ll explain why later) I’ll try to make my answer as short as possible. but first a little about me. I have a master degree in computer science, and I just finished my double major bachelor in applied math/economy. So; you probably can tell; I love science…(But I really hate software engineering). I was a software engineer for 14 years before I started a business and totally divorced SW Engineering . Yet I still code on the side, but I only code things that I love and fi Continue Reading First of all, You really need to know that at least 99.9% of ALL software engineers ARE NOT, and I REPEAT they ARE NOT Engineers in ANY way, shape or form! RARE are the architects that do Engineer a software solution and infrastructure! Don’t trust any answer in favor of SW engineering if its coming from a software engineer (I’ll explain why later) I’ll try to make my answer as short as possible. but first a little about me. I have a master degree in computer science, and I just finished my double major bachelor in applied math/economy. So; you probably can tell; I love science…(But I really hate software engineering). I was a software engineer for 14 years before I started a business and totally divorced SW Engineering . Yet I still code on the side, but I only code things that I love and fi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:07:18.277Z"),
    "question" : "Is software engineering a good career choice? I know it pays well initially, but if you look at the managing directors of most companies, they are people with MBAs. ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603695eb0c817f0398facd54"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-future-of-petroleum-engineering-as-a-career-choice?-",
    "answer" : "Let's start with the basics of Petroleum Engineering. The study of petroleum engineering can be broadly divided into two sectors:1. The Upstream Sector, deals with the exploration, production and exploitation of hydrocarbons (Petroleum and Natural gas).2. The Downstream Sector, deals with refining, marketing distribution. Most of the institutes in India offer petroleum engineering courses which cover the study of the upstream sector, whereas the downstream sector companies recruit chemical engineers. For the sake of this answer, I am going to refer to petroleum engineering as a course of the upstream sector. The demand of Petroleum products: We talk at lengths about unconventional renewable energy sources such as solar energy, wind energy etc. but to what amount are we actually using these Continue Reading Let's start with the basics of Petroleum Engineering. The study of petroleum engineering can be broadly divided into two sectors:1. The Upstream Sector, deals with the exploration, production and exploitation of hydrocarbons (Petroleum and Natural gas).2. The Downstream Sector, deals with refining, marketing distribution. Most of the institutes in India offer petroleum engineering courses which cover the study of the upstream sector, whereas the downstream sector companies recruit chemical engineers. For the sake of this answer, I am going to refer to petroleum engineering as a course of the upstream sector. The demand of Petroleum products: We talk at lengths about unconventional renewable energy sources such as solar energy, wind energy etc. but to what amount are we actually using these Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:07:39.102Z"),
    "question" : "What is the future of petroleum engineering as a career choice? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603696420c817f0398face87"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-of-being-a-Quality-Engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Sayed Shahnur A hardware quality engineers scope- In-circuit test (ICT)Stand-alone JTAG testAutomated x-ray inspection (AXI) (also known as X-ray test)Automated optical inspection (AOI) testContinuity or flying probe test(Board) functional test (BFT/FT)Burn-in testEnvironmental stress screening (ESS) testHighly Accelerated Life Test (HALT)Highly accelerated stress screening (HASS) testOngoing reliability test (ORT)System test (ST)Final quality audit process (FQA) test Software quality engineers scope- A software quality assurance engineer is involved in tasks that include software design, writing source code, control of source code, reviewing code, configuration management, change management, program testing, integration of the software, and release management process. A software quality assuran Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:09:06.052Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope of being a Quality Engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603696550c817f0398facea1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-way-to-start-the-carrier-as-a-civil-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Manoj Gowda First of all fresher will not be knowing present site scenario like technology, machineries, tools and construction materials. this is because some of our Indian institutes still feeds us the basic and expired methodologies. learning basics are good but not expired one. Here comes to your question, Search for a job in a well reputed companies attend for interviews irrespective of your interest because as civil engineer graduate you must work in site for a while until you become civil engineer. Try to brush up your theoretical knowledge and compare the same in the site, definitely you will come up with plenty of questions try to get the solutions for those, thus makes you a good engineer. After completing BE in civil engineering, Types of you will get site engineer quantity surveyor quality control  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:09:25.652Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best way to start the carrier as a civil engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036967e0c817f0398facf3a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-career-I-should-choose-whether-a-doctor-or-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Doctor is better. During our school days (70s and 80s), there were only two career options- engineering or medical. I chose the latter and became a doctor. I had the privilege to study medicine at CMC, Vellore, one of the best medical schools in our country. Subsequently, I did my specialization in Internal Medicine and super specialization in Neurology, also from CMC Vellore. I worked at CMC, Vellore for four years and later on moved to Apollo Hospital, Hyderabad, where I have been working for the past 14 years. I have spent a total of 29 years so far in medical profession (4.5 years as a medical student and 24.5 years as a doctor). If I had a chance to choose again, I would choose exactly the same. Reasons for liking doctor as a profession Making a difference to people’s lives on a daily basContinue Reading Doctor is better. During our school days (70s and 80s), there were only two career options- engineering or medical. I chose the latter and became a doctor. I had the privilege to study medicine at CMC, Vellore, one of the best medical schools in our country. Subsequently, I did my specialization in Internal Medicine and super specialization in Neurology, also from CMC Vellore. I worked at CMC, Vellore for four years and later on moved to Apollo Hospital, Hyderabad, where I have been working for the past 14 years. I have spent a total of 29 years so far in medical profession (4.5 years as a medical student and 24.5 years as a doctor). If I had a chance to choose again, I would choose exactly the same. Reasons for liking doctor as a profession Making a difference to people’s lives on a daily basContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:10:06.433Z"),
    "question" : "What career I should choose whether a doctor or engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603696a70c817f0398facf78"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-opportunities-after-completion-of-a-degree-in-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Ravindra Jadhav Mechanical engineering is the discipline which applies engineering, physics, materials science principles and engineering mathematics to design, analyse, manufacture, and maintain mechanical systems. This field of engineering is the oldest and broadest of all engineering fields and the job prospects for skilled mechanical engineers are copious and limitless in India and abroad. Training and education Requirements for Professionals Pursuing Mechanical Engineering Mechanical engineering encompasses a broad field of inter-disciplinary studies including major aspects of power generation, transportation, aerospace technology, and construction. Pursuing a career in mechanical engineering offers many benefits comprising excellent employment prospects, the opportunity for advancement, job security,  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:10:47.317Z"),
    "question" : "What are opportunities after completion of a degree in mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603696c00c817f0398facfee"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-backlog-in-any-subject-in-engineering-ruin-my-career?-",
    "answer" : "Shariq Qadri Do not worry for your backlog or SPI/CGPA . During engineering we see only small world around us where getting marks is the only solo goal. And its basically because of INDIAN mentality . People think being 9 pointer will give you job but its myth. Yes, if you have backlog then might you won’t able to sit in campus placement for few companies like TCS,Infosys etc… but again it depends on company carteria. i tell you the examples i seen during my campus recuritment. One of my friend got backlog in 7th sem and he was not so great in studies but he has excellent communication stills he talks with confident, and never jealous from toppers of his class and attends the party even if get backlog. during placements he got selected in Noida based company and today living independent and successful l Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:11:12.439Z"),
    "question" : "Can a backlog in any subject in engineering ruin my career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603696eb0c817f0398fad035"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-careers-associated-with-biomedical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Sammit Taklikar The visibility and impact of the management profession in healthcare has risen in recent years in view of the enabling systems and support it provides to direct-care professions such as nursing and medicine. After Biomedical Engineering , If a person wants to work in the management of Healthcare sector e.g. Medical devices,etc., should look forward in pursuing MBA Healthcare Management. Healthcare management gives a student thorough knowledge about Complex Healthcare industry which a normal MBA simply can not. Top healthcare management colleges in India include: 1. Goa Institute of Management - PGDM (Healthcare Management) 2. TATA Institute of Social Sciences TISS – Mumbai - MPH 3. The Institute of Health Management (IHMR)– Jaipur - Hospital Management TISS has two courses MPH- Master in Public H Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:11:55.577Z"),
    "question" : "What are the careers associated with biomedical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697010c817f0398fad0c3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-is-engineering-a-good-choice-of-profession?-",
    "answer" : "I write this article from my own personal experience of being an engineer who has seen all sides and opportunity besides engineering as well as engineering, now I'm a well established and skilled entrepreneur. Here is what I say… It's one of the best careers for people who are into the technical side… For everyone else you can say it's the worst in career in the world to choose. The reason I say the worst is because it's one thing to want to build a car and it's another thing to go out there and learn to build a car. First it's not that simple Second it's not easy( like anything else great) Third it's not free to accure that knowledge in a complete set without going and experimenting. Engineering is like an outdoor sport, in the sence it has the same elements of struggling and functions that resem Continue Reading I write this article from my own personal experience of being an engineer who has seen all sides and opportunity besides engineering as well as engineering, now I'm a well established and skilled entrepreneur. Here is what I say… It's one of the best careers for people who are into the technical side… For everyone else you can say it's the worst in career in the world to choose. The reason I say the worst is because it's one thing to want to build a car and it's another thing to go out there and learn to build a car. First it's not that simple Second it's not easy( like anything else great) Third it's not free to accure that knowledge in a complete set without going and experimenting. Engineering is like an outdoor sport, in the sence it has the same elements of struggling and functions that resem Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:12:17.610Z"),
    "question" : "Why is engineering a good choice of profession? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697180c817f0398fad0f7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-do-so-many-Indian-people-want-to-study-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Subhasish Ghosh Like most of my answers, I will try and be blatantly and bluntly and brutally honest. Unlike some of the other esteemed writers who have mentioned the ‘love for Indians for engineering’, ‘need for Engineers’ in India etc. which I consider nothing more than polished hogwash; the real reason for most students, especially coming from middle-class strata of society for choosing Engineering is… Read on. Indians as a race, are ostentatiously, unashamedly, unobtrusively, obsessively, fanatically, in love with the United States of America. It is the inherent dream of all parents; or the maximum of so, that if his/her kid can anyhow choose Engineering; it is the simplest and easiest way to eventually enter the USA and settle there. The land of dollars, and dreams. That is the fundamental reason. Here Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:12:40.591Z"),
    "question" : "Why do so many Indian people want to study engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697400c817f0398fad198"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-options-after-completing-a-BTech-in-electronics-and-communication-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Balajee I am discussing the same thing in the following post. Balajee's answer to I am an ECE 3rd year student. How can I understand the job market for ECE students?         Also all my posts are regarding the career for B.Tech ECE students. Here are few. I am a final year ECE B.Tech student wanting to go only into the ECE core field. How should I prepare and look for core jobs? Balajee's answer to I am an ECE 3rd year student. I am unable to link electrical and electronics. Where can I find an explanation? Balajee's answer to Why do people prefer software jobs after completing a BE/BTech in ECE or EEE or Mechanical instead of core jobs? Balajee's answer to What are the facts every ECE students should know? Balajee's answer to I am a final year ECE B.Tech student wanting to go only into the ECE core fiel Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:13:20.033Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career options after completing a BTech in electronics and communication engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697590c817f0398fad1c7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-scope-for-aeronautical-engineers-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Shiva Prakash Pendem",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:13:45.063Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any scope for aeronautical engineers in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697710c817f0398fad246"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-for-biomedical-engineering-in-india?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the scope for biomedical engineering in india?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:14:09.919Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope for biomedical engineering in india? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036979b0c817f0398fad28e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-of-environmental-engineering-after-getting-a-bachelor-degree?-",
    "answer" : "Yogendra Krisna Job profile of Environmental Engineering An environmental engineer is expected to specialize in fundamental sciences along with related aspects such as economics, ecology . Engineers who have a background in civil, electrical or mechanical engineering too have career opportunities in the field of environmental engineering. A qualified environmental engineering professional must know the designing, construction and waste maintenance techniques to preserve the health of rural, sub-urban and urban areas. Industrialization of a place leads to increase in environmental pollution and other hazards which are a threat to mankind. With rapid economic development India too has come to realize the role of environmental engineers to check the environmental hazards and create an ecological balance so th Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:14:51.117Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope of environmental engineering after getting a bachelor degree? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697c10c817f0398fad320"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-career-path-of-software-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Shyam Sunder Like an architect, understand what is the best possible representation for the problem at hand or for the feature or new project, and implement it.Implement clean code. Every single time.You would be responsible not just for the code you write but also for the code you inherit, and for the code your team produces. Make sure that you don't start using shitty APIs just because everybody else is, and obviously, make sure you don't produce them either.Keep revisiting your code and improve it as you go along. Monitor your existing processes with the right tools, and build those tools yourself if you have to.Document design discussions, meeting minutes, process details, change management notes and instructions for handling operational issues (ops). Everything.Also, by documenting you are making Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:15:29.374Z"),
    "question" : "What should be career path of software engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603697f40c817f0398fad3cc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-does-it-take-to-succeed-as-a-civil-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Ajinkya Mohod Persistence, Innovation, Patience: According to me this are the three traits which is important for any civil engineer to achieve success. If you look at E.Sreedharan, who is behind the execution of Konkan railway and Delhi metro which makes him the Metro Man of India, he worked more than his actual retirement period. Thus the persistence to achieve a specific goal had made this man so great. In the 21 st century the only way to survive in this running time is to change yourself with time. Along with change the key for success is innovation. Most of the companies got down in the market because they run on the traditional way and same work culture that they had before 50 yrs ago. But its not the fault of companies, the employees working in that company is responsible for that. The Construction Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:16:20.596Z"),
    "question" : "What does it take to succeed as a civil engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698150c817f0398fad409"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-future-jobs-which-I-can-join-after-the-completion-of-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "MOHD AIN As per my knowledge graduation in B.tech from Mechanical Engineering has many career options you can think of…… 1. Jobs in government sector These are the organisations, you can get a job by qualifying PSU( Public sector undertaking). This could include, various positions - ONGC (Oil & Natural Gas Corporation)DRDO (Defence Research and Development Organization)SAIL (Steel Authority of India)NTPC (National Thermal Power Corporation)VSSC (Vikram Sarabhai Space Center)ISRO (Indian Space Research Organisation) etc..2. GATE You can appear for the GATE exam. This could let you pursue: M.Tech or M.E. from IIT You can select one subject among these- Automobile EngineeringIndustrial EngineeringThermal EngineeringProduct Design and Development etc.3. Do an MBA MBA is quite a rage these days. Regardless of gr Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:16:53.455Z"),
    "question" : "What are the future jobs which I can join after the completion of mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698290c817f0398fad47d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-some-career-advice-that-you-can-give-for-an-aspiring-junior-software-engineer-to-succeed-in-their-career?-",
    "answer" : "Don't settle too early and don't artificially constraint yourself. For instance:Don't say I am a Java or .NET developer and restrict yourself to only those platformsDon't stay in the same company for too long, some times you settle for 1 year of experience repeated 5 times rather than 5 years of real experience. You can always come back to a company if you like it better than the next one. In large companies you can move to a different group.Don't move too fast, take the time to learn from the smart people around you. If you are the smartest person there leave immediately.Keep learning new and perspective changing technologies and not learn more of the same. For instance:If you know a object oriented language (C++) learn functional language like HaskellIf you know a statically typed languaContinue Reading Don't settle too early and don't artificially constraint yourself. For instance:Don't say I am a Java or .NET developer and restrict yourself to only those platformsDon't stay in the same company for too long, some times you settle for 1 year of experience repeated 5 times rather than 5 years of real experience. You can always come back to a company if you like it better than the next one. In large companies you can move to a different group.Don't move too fast, take the time to learn from the smart people around you. If you are the smartest person there leave immediately.Keep learning new and perspective changing technologies and not learn more of the same. For instance:If you know a object oriented language (C++) learn functional language like HaskellIf you know a statically typed languaContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:17:13.768Z"),
    "question" : "What is some career advice that you can give for an aspiring junior software engineer to succeed in their career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698470c817f0398fad4b6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-options-after-completing-agricultural-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "After doing graduation from renowned universities in india such as PAU , ICAR, TNAU , AGRU etc . Some companies come for placements in the 4th year (mahindra and mahindra, tafe , farm escorts, john deere etc. Companies visiting various campus is JOHN DEERE, MAHINDRA AND MAHINDRA, TAFE , FARM ESCORTS, VS TILLERs, NEW HOLLAND etc depend upon year to year. Max package was offered by john deere under marketing profile approx -5.5–6 LPA. Tafe and mahindra giving 4.5 lpa , farm escorts giving 4 lpa . In my batch 13 people got on campus placement all under marketing profile and approx 10–12 people got off campus placement under these companies or private tractor companies. Tractor companies recruit agricultural engineers mainly for their marketing and sales department. (Involves lots of travel).  Som Continue Reading After doing graduation from renowned universities in india such as PAU , ICAR, TNAU , AGRU etc . Some companies come for placements in the 4th year (mahindra and mahindra, tafe , farm escorts, john deere etc. Companies visiting various campus is JOHN DEERE, MAHINDRA AND MAHINDRA, TAFE , FARM ESCORTS, VS TILLERs, NEW HOLLAND etc depend upon year to year. Max package was offered by john deere under marketing profile approx -5.5–6 LPA. Tafe and mahindra giving 4.5 lpa , farm escorts giving 4 lpa . In my batch 13 people got on campus placement all under marketing profile and approx 10–12 people got off campus placement under these companies or private tractor companies. Tractor companies recruit agricultural engineers mainly for their marketing and sales department. (Involves lots of travel).  Som Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:17:43.655Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career options after completing agricultural engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036985d0c817f0398fad539"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-best-career-counseling-centres-in-Mumbai?-",
    "answer" : "Choosing the right career not only rewards you financially but also offers the desired professional growth. So, as a student, we all are quite conscious regarding the career that we are going to choose. But many students including me are not able to make the right career choice without any proper guidance. Sanjeevni Career Guidance & Counselling which is the best career counselling center in Mumbai is the most appropriate destination for students like me who are confused about their career preferences and options. Living in a metro city like Mumbai, one can have a list of career counselling centers but there is a reason behind why I chose this particular center. One day I was just sitting and thinking that which type of career would be suitable for me as I had kept very limited career choic Continue Reading Choosing the right career not only rewards you financially but also offers the desired professional growth. So, as a student, we all are quite conscious regarding the career that we are going to choose. But many students including me are not able to make the right career choice without any proper guidance. Sanjeevni Career Guidance & Counselling which is the best career counselling center in Mumbai is the most appropriate destination for students like me who are confused about their career preferences and options. Living in a metro city like Mumbai, one can have a list of career counselling centers but there is a reason behind why I chose this particular center. One day I was just sitting and thinking that which type of career would be suitable for me as I had kept very limited career choic Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:18:05.347Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best career counseling centres in Mumbai? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698710c817f0398fad559"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-good-is-aircraft-maintenance-engineering-for-a-career?-",
    "answer" : "Shubham Kumar Saurav, M.Tech Operations Research, National Institute of Technology Durgapur (2019)Answered 1 year agoHow good is aircraft maintenance engineering for a career? Shubham Kumar Saurav As a career perspective, aircraft maintenance engineering is a booming industry and it can give you, your dream salary. But, if you are interested in this course, you will enjoy your whole life with a huge salary. Lots of people thinks that it is a diploma in aircraft maintenance engineering but the fact is aircraft maintenance course is a licence program. If you are planning to join this course, follow the list of mandatory qualifications. Mandatory qualification includes – 1. 10+2 Pass with Physics, Chemistry, and Mathematics as major subjects. 2. Minimum age at the time of course registration is sixteen years. 3. Medical fitness certificate issued by Registered Medical Practitioner is essential at the time of admission. 4. Candidates who have passed diploma in Mechanical, Electrical, Electro Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:18:25.032Z"),
    "question" : "How good is aircraft maintenance engineering for a career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698840c817f0398fad57d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-software-engineering-a-dead-end-career?-Many-programmers-find-that-their-employability-begins-to-decline-around-age-35,-and-they’re-out-of-the-field-by-40.-",
    "answer" : "I am writing this from an Indian angle. Here the IT industry started during late 80's during which Indian economy started to open an we became from a socialist economy to capitalist economy. Infosys and TCS hired by tens of thousands people to do mediocre coding and support jobs. The first generation which joined these companies moved away from these jobs quickly and become managers by the early 2000s. Anyways they were not technical at all and rode this new wave of capitalism. They made 20 times what there fathers made in the socialist economy and were more then happy to manage people. For them it was going abroad and having 3 flats at Bangalore doing mediocre managerial job. They mostly succeeded in doing so. But the path which they had created for the second generation which started in m Continue Reading I am writing this from an Indian angle. Here the IT industry started during late 80's during which Indian economy started to open an we became from a socialist economy to capitalist economy. Infosys and TCS hired by tens of thousands people to do mediocre coding and support jobs. The first generation which joined these companies moved away from these jobs quickly and become managers by the early 2000s. Anyways they were not technical at all and rode this new wave of capitalism. They made 20 times what there fathers made in the socialist economy and were more then happy to manage people. For them it was going abroad and having 3 flats at Bangalore doing mediocre managerial job. They mostly succeeded in doing so. But the path which they had created for the second generation which started in m Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:18:44.610Z"),
    "question" : "Is software engineering a dead end career? Many programmers find that their employability begins to decline around age 35, and they’re out of the field by 40. ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698aa0c817f0398fad624"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-being-a-software-engineer-fun?-",
    "answer" : "Being a software engineer is fun if you enjoy software engineering 🙂 Joking aside, this is a quite subjective question and whether one enjoys being a software engineer has largely to do with their personality and preferences. For example, being a software engineer will be fun if you: enjoy understanding how things work in detail, taking them apart and assembling them again.are analytical.love solving riddles.like continously learning new things.Being a software engineer might not be fun if you: like staying in your comfort zone.are typically looking for easy answers and you are rarely intrigued to learn how things work under the hood.I won’t lie, being a software engineer comes with its own challenges: You have to constantly stay up-to-date with new technologies sometimes at the expense of youContinue Reading Being a software engineer is fun if you enjoy software engineering 🙂 Joking aside, this is a quite subjective question and whether one enjoys being a software engineer has largely to do with their personality and preferences. For example, being a software engineer will be fun if you: enjoy understanding how things work in detail, taking them apart and assembling them again.are analytical.love solving riddles.like continously learning new things.Being a software engineer might not be fun if you: like staying in your comfort zone.are typically looking for easy answers and you are rarely intrigued to learn how things work under the hood.I won’t lie, being a software engineer comes with its own challenges: You have to constantly stay up-to-date with new technologies sometimes at the expense of youContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:19:22.902Z"),
    "question" : "Is being a software engineer fun? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698d40c817f0398fad6d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-can-I-do-after-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Mandiga Nagendra So you wanna know about what you can do after B.tech in mechanical engineering. There are many options to choose from, it took me quite a time to decide what to do with my mech engg degree. There is usually some skills still lacking which need to be overcome to abridge the gap between your degree and industry. PG Diploma courses:There out some institutes where you can get trained in courses like master in CAD/ mechatronics/ advance machining. The courses usually are for 6/12 months.CITD,HyderabadNTTF- This is the only place i could find with PG diploma in automotive designCTTCCIPET2. M.Tech: Masters in india from tier 1 and tier 2 colleges are reasonable. Better try out IIT /NIT via GATE. 3.Design Intern/Master certification: In automotive design / aerospace which is domain specific like BIW ,eContinue Reading So you wanna know about what you can do after B.tech in mechanical engineering. There are many options to choose from, it took me quite a time to decide what to do with my mech engg degree. There is usually some skills still lacking which need to be overcome to abridge the gap between your degree and industry. PG Diploma courses:There out some institutes where you can get trained in courses like master in CAD/ mechatronics/ advance machining. The courses usually are for 6/12 months.CITD,HyderabadNTTF- This is the only place i could find with PG diploma in automotive designCTTCCIPET2. M.Tech: Masters in india from tier 1 and tier 2 colleges are reasonable. Better try out IIT /NIT via GATE. 3.Design Intern/Master certification: In automotive design / aerospace which is domain specific like BIW ,eContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:20:04.828Z"),
    "question" : "What can I do after mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603698ee0c817f0398fad701"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-country-for-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best country for mechanical engineering?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:20:30.689Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best country for mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699040c817f0398fad72e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-prospects-for-women-pursuing-degrees-in-civil-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "I'll enlist what all you can do with your bachelors degree in civil engineering. You decide what to do. You have many options once you complete civil engineering in India(I don't know much about the opportunities abroad)  which can place you in a better position. 1. GATE : You can give it a try. (If you are so desperate to do M.Tech in some of the reputed institutions in India) M.Tech in Transportation Engineering M.Tech in Structural Engineering M.Tech in Water Resource Engineering M.Tech in Geo-Technical engineering M.Tech in Environmental Engineering etc 2. IES : Indian Engineering Services. Believe me. You are now eligible to apply. (Even Civils) 3. PSU : If you are technically strong, you can apply for PSU's. Nowadays they are mainly dependent on GATE score. So, prepare hard for GATE. Give your Continue Reading I'll enlist what all you can do with your bachelors degree in civil engineering. You decide what to do. You have many options once you complete civil engineering in India(I don't know much about the opportunities abroad)  which can place you in a better position. 1. GATE : You can give it a try. (If you are so desperate to do M.Tech in some of the reputed institutions in India) M.Tech in Transportation Engineering M.Tech in Structural Engineering M.Tech in Water Resource Engineering M.Tech in Geo-Technical engineering M.Tech in Environmental Engineering etc 2. IES : Indian Engineering Services. Believe me. You are now eligible to apply. (Even Civils) 3. PSU : If you are technically strong, you can apply for PSU's. Nowadays they are mainly dependent on GATE score. So, prepare hard for GATE. Give your Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:20:52.617Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career prospects for women pursuing degrees in civil engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699150c817f0398fad7a0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-Electrical-Engineering-a-good-career-option?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is Electrical Engineering a good career option?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:21:09.665Z"),
    "question" : "Is Electrical Engineering a good career option? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699280c817f0398fad7c6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-prestigious-is-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "I am a PhD Chemical Engineer and have been for almost 20 years. I understand your question well. I would say this is NOT low prestige, but the prestige is sliding and is not where it should be. I have managed teams of scientists and engineers all over the world and my experience is as follows: The average person doesn’t understand what we do. And they don’t understand how how hard this degree is or how many students fail out of this degree at university. Further more, many people without engineering degrees work at a plant for a few years, do a great job, and then get promoted into an engineering titled role. It is unfortunate that no title exists with which to reward these highly skilled and hard working technicians or operators. As a result these counterfeit engineers, even though they may  Continue Reading I am a PhD Chemical Engineer and have been for almost 20 years. I understand your question well. I would say this is NOT low prestige, but the prestige is sliding and is not where it should be. I have managed teams of scientists and engineers all over the world and my experience is as follows: The average person doesn’t understand what we do. And they don’t understand how how hard this degree is or how many students fail out of this degree at university. Further more, many people without engineering degrees work at a plant for a few years, do a great job, and then get promoted into an engineering titled role. It is unfortunate that no title exists with which to reward these highly skilled and hard working technicians or operators. As a result these counterfeit engineers, even though they may  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:21:28.076Z"),
    "question" : "How prestigious is engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036993d0c817f0398fad7f0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-career-advice-given-to-an-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "I have already answered similar question several times and repeating the same for you. All branches of engineering will have specialization areas. You decide that in which area of your branch, you want to concentrate and work. You will have to learn a lot in that area. Try to be a performer (to become a performer you need to be meticulous in your task). Each day (except week ends - plan of action during these two days must be scheduled separately) you will have to effectively utilize or spend the available 14 to 16 hours(7 hours at college and 7 to 9 hours at home /hostel) in the following manner: [I] At your college (during your class hours) the following tips will be of some use: [1] Be regular to all of your classes, because you are sure to get something if not everything. And that will be  Continue Reading I have already answered similar question several times and repeating the same for you. All branches of engineering will have specialization areas. You decide that in which area of your branch, you want to concentrate and work. You will have to learn a lot in that area. Try to be a performer (to become a performer you need to be meticulous in your task). Each day (except week ends - plan of action during these two days must be scheduled separately) you will have to effectively utilize or spend the available 14 to 16 hours(7 hours at college and 7 to 9 hours at home /hostel) in the following manner: [I] At your college (during your class hours) the following tips will be of some use: [1] Be regular to all of your classes, because you are sure to get something if not everything. And that will be  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:21:49.150Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best career advice given to an engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036994e0c817f0398fad868"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-of-computer-science-engineering-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "As the world is shrinking and is becoming more and more digital, the scope for Computer Science is on a rise. You must have heard people from other specializations (Mechanical, Civil, Electronics, etc.) working in the Computer Science area. While according to NASSCOM, by 2020, the Indian IT exports are expected to expand to the tune of US$ 175 billion. The domestic sector will account for US$ 50 billion!!! Positions/ Job Opportunities in various fields There are various areas where you can work, depending upon your interest and vacancy in the market.Software DevelopersSoftware TestingData ArchitectDatabase DeveloperData ModelerQuality Assurance Associate / AnalystMobile Applications DeveloperUI/UX DesignerSoftware Quality Assurance (QA)Game DesignerWebsite/ Mobile Application DesignerInforma Continue Reading As the world is shrinking and is becoming more and more digital, the scope for Computer Science is on a rise. You must have heard people from other specializations (Mechanical, Civil, Electronics, etc.) working in the Computer Science area. While according to NASSCOM, by 2020, the Indian IT exports are expected to expand to the tune of US$ 175 billion. The domestic sector will account for US$ 50 billion!!! Positions/ Job Opportunities in various fields There are various areas where you can work, depending upon your interest and vacancy in the market.Software DevelopersSoftware TestingData ArchitectDatabase DeveloperData ModelerQuality Assurance Associate / AnalystMobile Applications DeveloperUI/UX DesignerSoftware Quality Assurance (QA)Game DesignerWebsite/ Mobile Application DesignerInforma Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:22:06.670Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope of computer science engineering in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699680c817f0398fad898"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-options-if-I-am-not-interested-in-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Here are some other alternatives - Teaching- I give this the first priority. I ll give you the reasons too. Everyone these days are interested in the their own goodwill. They just want to become engineers or doctors or other people who hold power in the society,so that they can earn cores and crores of rupees and thus get settled. That's what everyone desires and nobody cares about other professions. Sad part is that they don't even respect other professions. teaching is a very good profession. You can be grateful cause you get to teach lakhs of students in your career. Also you get experience through the years which is incomparable. Now there is deficiency in this particular department. Teaching doesn't imply just teaching kids. It includes everyone who teaches students..like they can be tContinue Reading Here are some other alternatives - Teaching- I give this the first priority. I ll give you the reasons too. Everyone these days are interested in the their own goodwill. They just want to become engineers or doctors or other people who hold power in the society,so that they can earn cores and crores of rupees and thus get settled. That's what everyone desires and nobody cares about other professions. Sad part is that they don't even respect other professions. teaching is a very good profession. You can be grateful cause you get to teach lakhs of students in your career. Also you get experience through the years which is incomparable. Now there is deficiency in this particular department. Teaching doesn't imply just teaching kids. It includes everyone who teaches students..like they can be tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:22:32.980Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career options if I am not interested in engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6036998b0c817f0398fad933"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-engineering-a-better-career-option-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "Ashish Agarwal, MCA Master of Computer Applications, Assam Engineering College (2021)Answered 1 year agoIs engineering a better career option in India? Ashish Agarwal No, you cannot say that. No profession is better than the other it totally depends on the individual how they pursue their profession. If you are interested in your field you will definitely do well in that particular field. It's just that engineering in India is considered to be a prestigious field but since most of the engineers are either unemployed or working in a non-engineering field. And those who choose their fields by choice are successful in their respective fields. So it totally depends on your passion for anything. People are doing good in the art field, sports, be it any field as long as you are passionate you can excel in any profession.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:23:07.538Z"),
    "question" : "Is engineering a better career option in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699a00c817f0398fad95b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-alternative-careers-exist-for-a-mechanical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What alternative careers exist for a mechanical engineer?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:23:28.027Z"),
    "question" : "What alternative careers exist for a mechanical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699b40c817f0398fad981"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-opportunities-for-IT-engineering-students?-",
    "answer" : "Rajiv Kumar Information technology has entered and benefited all sectors of industry. IT professionals design, support, and maintain computer hardware and software for various industrial and individual applications and are much sought after for their expertise and experience.Career paths in the IT industry can be broadly classified into the two main fields of hardware and software. Under hardware, you have manufacturing, maintenance, research and development, and management. Under software, you have manufacturing, development, programming, software testing, and maintenance and support. Among related areas are computer operations, database administration, sales/marketing, and data-center management. Popular job designations include computer hardware engineer, software engineer, information systems manag Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:23:48.044Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career opportunities for IT engineering students? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699cb0c817f0398fad9fb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-jobs-for-a-chemical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "What you mean by best job???? Best salaryBest satisfactionBest learningEtc….According to me best job is in which you learn continuously and give your 100% because company pay for that and at the end of the day you feel satisfied for what you did for the whole day. If you are chemical engineer then you have many option to start your professional carrier like Production(Reliance,PSU,Pharmaceutical)Designing(Linde and L&T)ISROBARCDRDOTeachingResearchConsultancyYou have so many option but you have to chooes as per you INTEREST. If you are interested in your job and you love your job then i can say yes this is the best job for you. When we have to choose we select the job in which we get better salary and we put our interest a side. We do the same thing for the entire life and everyday come back to  Continue Reading What you mean by best job???? Best salaryBest satisfactionBest learningEtc….According to me best job is in which you learn continuously and give your 100% because company pay for that and at the end of the day you feel satisfied for what you did for the whole day. If you are chemical engineer then you have many option to start your professional carrier like Production(Reliance,PSU,Pharmaceutical)Designing(Linde and L&T)ISROBARCDRDOTeachingResearchConsultancyYou have so many option but you have to chooes as per you INTEREST. If you are interested in your job and you love your job then i can say yes this is the best job for you. When we have to choose we select the job in which we get better salary and we put our interest a side. We do the same thing for the entire life and everyday come back to  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:24:11.856Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best jobs for a chemical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603699e00c817f0398fada24"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-a-career-as-Embedded-Engineer-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "Excellent opportunity. Few companies are listed by Rekka Vijayakumar in her answer. There are lot more companies are also there. But prepare yourself thoroughly  before sending your resume to these companies. Here is a checklist               1. Good C programming skill              2. Good knowledge on processor architecture              3. I2C/SPI/PCIe knowledge              4. NOR Flash/NAND Flash knowledge              5. Networking fundamentals              6. Knowledge in Linux Internals will have added advantage              7. Virtual Memory/Physical Memory Knowledge                                     All the best",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:24:32.508Z"),
    "question" : "How is a career as Embedded Engineer in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369a190c817f0398fadadd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-future-career-prospects-in-civil-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Civil engineering is the one of the very oldest professional degree in the field of engineering. From the construction of building, roads, airport, harbor, dam, canal, reservoir, metro railway track all are the workplace for civil engineers. There are various carrier option as following: 1.\tStart a civil engineering consultancy and construction firm– It requires potential to do something and also requiremore practical knowledge of construction. Civil engineers can team to innovate and come up with ideas that better the design and construction procedure. 2.\tStart A job in a private sector – you can start a job in a construction company, real estate, infrastructure and project industry as a site engineer or for any profile which suits your academics, like CAD, billing etc. 3.\tHigher education – Continue Reading Civil engineering is the one of the very oldest professional degree in the field of engineering. From the construction of building, roads, airport, harbor, dam, canal, reservoir, metro railway track all are the workplace for civil engineers. There are various carrier option as following: 1.\tStart a civil engineering consultancy and construction firm– It requires potential to do something and also requiremore practical knowledge of construction. Civil engineers can team to innovate and come up with ideas that better the design and construction procedure. 2.\tStart A job in a private sector – you can start a job in a construction company, real estate, infrastructure and project industry as a site engineer or for any profile which suits your academics, like CAD, billing etc. 3.\tHigher education – Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:25:29.019Z"),
    "question" : "What are the future career prospects in civil engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369a400c817f0398fadb7b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-good-non-technical-job-options-for-engineers-to-pursue-career-in?-",
    "answer" : "If by non-technical you mean Profiles not related to Engineering: Looking at Finance I'd say Treasury Management (being a Trader or Stock Broker) would be one of the most lucrative options since you'll be using your technical background to run calculations and look for opportunities to make quick gains in the market.Similarly, Risk Management would again be a good option, but probably at a more senior level. Again, Management Consulting would also open up based on your aptitude and if you would have the base for some critical thinking and problem solving. They ideally help firms in aspects like cost reduction, profit maximisation, etc. and have to think about a lot of things from a holistic point of view.  I would not put Investment Banking or Corporate Finance in the same league as they requ Continue Reading If by non-technical you mean Profiles not related to Engineering: Looking at Finance I'd say Treasury Management (being a Trader or Stock Broker) would be one of the most lucrative options since you'll be using your technical background to run calculations and look for opportunities to make quick gains in the market.Similarly, Risk Management would again be a good option, but probably at a more senior level. Again, Management Consulting would also open up based on your aptitude and if you would have the base for some critical thinking and problem solving. They ideally help firms in aspects like cost reduction, profit maximisation, etc. and have to think about a lot of things from a holistic point of view.  I would not put Investment Banking or Corporate Finance in the same league as they requ Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:26:08.681Z"),
    "question" : "What are some good non-technical job options for engineers to pursue career in? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369a5c0c817f0398fadbae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-earning-career-options-under-PCM-except-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Gagan Kaur Dear student, Well, Majority of students with a PCM combination in class XII aspire to pursue engineering, and often struggle with the thought, “If not engineering, then what?” Many PCM students naturally drift towards engineering after 12th, partially because they never actually stop to evaluate their options, and partially because they have been led by their parents/friends/the society to believe that engineering is the end-all, be-all of a PCM student. So i am here to guide you: Architecture: Career Opportunities in Architecture: You can choose to specialise in numerous sub-fields, such as ART IN ARCHITECTUREDESIGN AND THEORYGLASS ARCHITECTURE AND DESIGNHOUSINGINTERIOR DESIGNPLANNING WORKSHOPTHEATRE AND FILM SET DESIGNURBAN DESIGNSome Top Colleges for Architecture: School of Planning and ArchiContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:26:36.243Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best earning career options under PCM except engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369a790c817f0398fadc42"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-decide-what-to-do-after-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "I have already answered similar question earlier, and repeating the same for you. [1] Most of the organizations will be looking forward for the performers. Your focus should be on how to become a good performer. [2] Do not concentrate only on very big core companies. Have the Resume, give your Resume to the people (who are either working or having contact with the employers) you know. [3] Join any one of medium scale companies (Please, do not worry/bother much about the initial salary-always remember that \"Great/big things have come out of small things\"). [4] With some experience in small or medium industries, things are going to be very smooth(do not worry much about your initial salary). Treat that as a 'training period\", and \"investment\". [5] You can think of joining any industry, which you  Continue Reading I have already answered similar question earlier, and repeating the same for you. [1] Most of the organizations will be looking forward for the performers. Your focus should be on how to become a good performer. [2] Do not concentrate only on very big core companies. Have the Resume, give your Resume to the people (who are either working or having contact with the employers) you know. [3] Join any one of medium scale companies (Please, do not worry/bother much about the initial salary-always remember that \"Great/big things have come out of small things\"). [4] With some experience in small or medium industries, things are going to be very smooth(do not worry much about your initial salary). Treat that as a 'training period\", and \"investment\". [5] You can think of joining any industry, which you  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:27:05.204Z"),
    "question" : "How do I decide what to do after engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369a9b0c817f0398fadc81"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-career-path-for-an-engineer-to-become-a-CEO?-",
    "answer" : "Ted Pryor There is no doubt an engineer can become CEO particularly if engineering is an important part of the company’s core compentancy. The trick is that you need to move to the business side over time and that inevitably leads away from being an engineer on a daily basis. Some people just want to be engineers or lawyers or architects, or newspaper reporters and don't want to manage the business. If you want to run the business you must build your resume in the following ways: First you must learn to be a manager of people and that means looking for roles where you are managing other engineers. A team of 2–3 to start and then more as your skills progress.Second you must eventually be involved in the strategic necessities of the running a business. A good way for an engineer to do this is product deContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:27:39.379Z"),
    "question" : "What is the career path for an engineer to become a CEO? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369ae10c817f0398fadd6f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-technical-support-engineer-a-good-job?-",
    "answer" : "I would say absolutely. You will learn, be challenged, and you will grow in technical, analytical, business, and people skills. There is no other position like it. People look down on it but it is foundational for any IT career. As far as liking it … like any job, I liked some things about it and didn’t like some. I was in tech support for about 2.5 years in what I later found out was an L3 type position that was more creative (that was probably why I liked it so much). I liked helping the customers, learning the tech, and figuring out how to solve customer problems. I also was able to challenge myself to learn all sorts of cool stuff. I learned a lot about what I liked (customers are cool, learning new tech, influencing the direction of the product, leading people) and what I didn’t like ( Continue Reading I would say absolutely. You will learn, be challenged, and you will grow in technical, analytical, business, and people skills. There is no other position like it. People look down on it but it is foundational for any IT career. As far as liking it … like any job, I liked some things about it and didn’t like some. I was in tech support for about 2.5 years in what I later found out was an L3 type position that was more creative (that was probably why I liked it so much). I liked helping the customers, learning the tech, and figuring out how to solve customer problems. I also was able to challenge myself to learn all sorts of cool stuff. I learned a lot about what I liked (customers are cool, learning new tech, influencing the direction of the product, leading people) and what I didn’t like ( Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:28:49.354Z"),
    "question" : "Is technical support engineer a good job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369b0d0c817f0398fade16"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-become-a-good-machine-learning-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "You have been taking the right courses. Have you done any capstone projects in any of these classes? There is a difference between learning theoretically and solving real world problems so you should take steps to give you experience in the latter. Its not just for your resume, but working on real customer use cases and the scale of data will shape your knowledge to get you ready for the real world. These are three steps you can take towards that - Apply your knowledge to recreate a published ML research work. For example typically you see examples of understanding housing prices or something like that pointing to a data set. It does not teach you where you hone your skills because your goal is not theoretical. (Thanks to Siraj Raval of Sirajology for this suggestion). Find a paper from arxivContinue Reading You have been taking the right courses. Have you done any capstone projects in any of these classes? There is a difference between learning theoretically and solving real world problems so you should take steps to give you experience in the latter. Its not just for your resume, but working on real customer use cases and the scale of data will shape your knowledge to get you ready for the real world. These are three steps you can take towards that - Apply your knowledge to recreate a published ML research work. For example typically you see examples of understanding housing prices or something like that pointing to a data set. It does not teach you where you hone your skills because your goal is not theoretical. (Thanks to Siraj Raval of Sirajology for this suggestion). Find a paper from arxivContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:29:33.469Z"),
    "question" : "How can one become a good machine learning engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369b270c817f0398fade49"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-kind-of-engineering-pays-the-most?-",
    "answer" : "Pooja Here's a list (in chorological order), of the top (read that as highest paying) engineering branches along with the reasoning of it being the best: Computer Science Engineering: In India R&D, innovation and electronics manufacturing sectors are very weak and do not provide enough opportunities to engineers of electronics, chemical, textile, instrumentation, bio-medical and aeronautical branches. However, service sector is the strongest as per job opportunities and commercial gains. Be it banking, airlines, insurance, railways, hospitals, hospitality or IT field; every where there is a requirement of software solution. The billions of devices produced in every sector from automobile to aerospace need microprocessor control, which are software driven. It is not only development or coding of th Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:29:59.764Z"),
    "question" : "What kind of engineering pays the most? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369bad0c817f0398fae040"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-careers-that-software-engineers-can-transition-to?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are some careers that software engineers can transition to?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:32:13.005Z"),
    "question" : "What are some careers that software engineers can transition to? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369bc10c817f0398fae06b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-can-a-tired-and-stressed-out-software-engineer-choose-as-a-next-career?-",
    "answer" : "Harry Keller I love a couple of the answers so far. As someone who has been writing software, mostly, since 1960 and professionally since 1974, I also have tried out plenty of careers during my lifetime. Here’s a quick summary. Graduate student: wrote huge FORTRAN numerical analysis program (summing divergent series) for thesis. Industrial research scientist: great job, nice people, occasional challenges (some involving me writing software) but dull environment. Wife also had a job there programming and hated it. Chemistry professor: loved the students, hated the school politics (large university), and was not clued into the methodology of grant writing. Left after four years. Principal programmer for big computer company: first professional software job. Software supervisor: same company. Software manager ( Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:32:33.811Z"),
    "question" : "What can a tired and stressed out software engineer choose as a next career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369bd30c817f0398fae093"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-highest-paid-career-routes-for-engineers?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Rick Kitson",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:32:51.269Z"),
    "question" : "What are the highest paid career routes for engineers? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369be40c817f0398fae10d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-an-engineering-student-switch-careers-to-finance?-",
    "answer" : "Qualifications: IITB students working in a quantitative finance role in a global investment bank. Finance is a very broad field with diverse roles. Different roles require different skill-set and aptitude. Hence I recommend that you get a birds eye view of different sectors. There are many (free) resources available here on the internet. Try browsing Quora- follow relevant topics and top authors in those fields. They are usually experts with a wide range of knowledge and experience. Other than Quora there are websites like Poets and Quants, Wall Street Oasis, which share different perspectives on such fields. You can follow any of the following strategies depending on the field you zero in on. Quantitative Finance: This is the most common field among IITians and specifically among EE, CS an Continue Reading Qualifications: IITB students working in a quantitative finance role in a global investment bank. Finance is a very broad field with diverse roles. Different roles require different skill-set and aptitude. Hence I recommend that you get a birds eye view of different sectors. There are many (free) resources available here on the internet. Try browsing Quora- follow relevant topics and top authors in those fields. They are usually experts with a wide range of knowledge and experience. Other than Quora there are websites like Poets and Quants, Wall Street Oasis, which share different perspectives on such fields. You can follow any of the following strategies depending on the field you zero in on. Quantitative Finance: This is the most common field among IITians and specifically among EE, CS an Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:33:08.095Z"),
    "question" : "How can an engineering student switch careers to finance? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369bf80c817f0398fae131"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-prospects-for-an-Electronics-and-Communication-Engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Hey Buddy Good question, many students wants know about after ECE, Thanks for asking this question…!!! Electronics and Communication engineering is one of the old and the best course in the field of engineering. This article provides Career Guidance, Choices, Career development strategies, Job Opportunities, Salary and Skills Required in the field of Electronics and Communication for ECE, MSc Electronics students to make a successful career.  Electronics and Communication cover vast areas in the field of engineering. It is not possible for a person to become an expert in all the fields. So, one should choose one or two areas of interest from the list of sub fields given below, which is close to your heart. Also, to keep you updated about latest technologies and inventions in this domain, go th Continue Reading Hey Buddy Good question, many students wants know about after ECE, Thanks for asking this question…!!! Electronics and Communication engineering is one of the old and the best course in the field of engineering. This article provides Career Guidance, Choices, Career development strategies, Job Opportunities, Salary and Skills Required in the field of Electronics and Communication for ECE, MSc Electronics students to make a successful career.  Electronics and Communication cover vast areas in the field of engineering. It is not possible for a person to become an expert in all the fields. So, one should choose one or two areas of interest from the list of sub fields given below, which is close to your heart. Also, to keep you updated about latest technologies and inventions in this domain, go th Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:33:28.100Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career prospects for an Electronics and Communication Engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369c0c0c817f0398fae157"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-career-ladder-for-software-engineers?-",
    "answer" : "Christopher Burke A “career ladder” is a directed graph of the lateral transfer and promotion opportunities available to a person with a given job title. The graph, job titles, and parity between technical and management titles vary from company to company. For example, at a hypothetical company that isn’t flat: A Junior Engineer can be promoted to EngineerAn Engineer can be promoted to Senior EngineerA Senior Engineer can be promoted to Lead EngineerA Lead Engineer can be promoted either to Staff Engineer, or to Engineering ManagerIn this hypothetical example we’ve reached a “fork” in the career ladder. At some companies this “fork” ends the engineering ladder; to advance a person must take on management positions. At other companies, this “fork” marks the beginning of a “dual career ladder” with both a “tec Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:33:48.363Z"),
    "question" : "What is the career ladder for software engineers? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369c590c817f0398fae292"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-opportunities-for-chemical-engineering-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "Anish L In layman's term, A chemical engineer is a guy that helps in the production of things on a large scale. He is one which studies a process, design plant, and equipment and also runs the plant. As you see I have divided work into three broad categories and the job conditions are different for these. Let us tackle them one by one- Research - You will find many chemical engineers involve in research. These are the guys that study processes and try to find out the best way to produce a thing on a large level, both safely and economically. They also try to improve existing processes.Some of the guys also work in hardcore science like ionic chemistry (battery etc.) , nanotechnology, biotechnology (yup chemical engineers have really very wide options when it comes to research.) If you have an inter Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:35:05.450Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job opportunities for chemical engineering in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369c7b0c817f0398fae2cd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-did-you-choose-to-be-an-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Why did you choose to be an engineer?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:35:39.441Z"),
    "question" : "Why did you choose to be an engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369cad0c817f0398fae3a6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-VLSI-engineer-a-dead-end-career?-",
    "answer" : "Mohd Muktadar Mohiuddin This is my perspective and completely based on my experiences. First, I agree that the industry has started slowing down. This is because of physical limitation of the silicon technology. We as researchers have not yet found a material that can replace silicon or have not yet perfected Quantum computing (although promising it is far from becoming true). However, I disagree with those who believe that the industry will die or collapse. Fundamental reason is, VLSI is the foundation of all industry! If VLSI collapses (Chip industry or silicon industry comes under same domain), then rest of the industry will eventually collapse due to mere dependence of computers! So, the industry has to stay and it will. Innovations and creativity required to work on this industry would increase. Rapid changes  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:36:29.678Z"),
    "question" : "Is VLSI engineer a dead end career? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369cd80c817f0398fae457"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-career-growth-in-Wipro-Technologies-as-a-project-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Veera Suresh As a project engineer, First year : you are thrilled and excited to be part of a tier 1 company and amazed by the IT campus and facilities on offer.  You work hard, eager to prove your worth, sometimes till 10-11pm in night. Your team lead praises you, project manager applauds you..Second year : You are excited by last years appraisals which gives you the top rating, you are eager to repeat the success.  Seniors in the team, in the name of exposure gives you bits and bits of their own work.  You don't mind, anxious to leave your mark in team and project.  Third year : small things like back pain and occasional migraine has started troubling you but you are ready to give your blood and sweat for the project.  You are slightly troubled as appreciation for your hardwork is taken over by on Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:37:12.952Z"),
    "question" : "What is the career growth in Wipro Technologies as a project engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369cfd0c817f0398fae4a9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-future-for-electronics-and-communication-engineers?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best future for electronics and communication engineers?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:37:49.064Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best future for electronics and communication engineers? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d200c817f0398fae543"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-after-doing-aircraft-maintenance-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Practically Nothing!! Until & unless you know someone really influential in civil aviation, it's of no use to do AME. To cite an example I did AME from a college in Pune. The college ran in a 500 square yards building where the owner of house lived on ground floor and our college which was on rent had its admin block, library, labs, classes, hostel and mess on 1st, 2nd, 3rd and top floor of the same house. AME is a specialized license course, so if you don't get a job in civil aviation you might end up wasting 3 crucial years of your life. It holds no significance outside civil aviation sector. Although AME is a technical course, it doesn't include Engineering Mathematics in its curriculum. The semester mark sheets which I got from there were handwritten which sometimes feel forged. I gave ₹10, Continue Reading Practically Nothing!! Until & unless you know someone really influential in civil aviation, it's of no use to do AME. To cite an example I did AME from a college in Pune. The college ran in a 500 square yards building where the owner of house lived on ground floor and our college which was on rent had its admin block, library, labs, classes, hostel and mess on 1st, 2nd, 3rd and top floor of the same house. AME is a specialized license course, so if you don't get a job in civil aviation you might end up wasting 3 crucial years of your life. It holds no significance outside civil aviation sector. Although AME is a technical course, it doesn't include Engineering Mathematics in its curriculum. The semester mark sheets which I got from there were handwritten which sometimes feel forged. I gave ₹10, Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:38:24.072Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope after doing aircraft maintenance engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d330c817f0398fae564"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-overall-top-engineering-colleges?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Shilpa Suri",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:38:43.178Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the overall top engineering colleges? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d530c817f0398fae601"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-job-for-an-electrical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best job for an electrical engineer?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:39:15.432Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best job for an electrical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d680c817f0398fae62a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-career-opportunities-after-studying-electronics-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "There is bound to be huge demand for competent engineers in electronic industry to cope this demand in technology. The engineers would be involved in sustaining cutting edge technology to stay ahead in competition. Electronics have a major role to play in virtually every industry. They increase productivity in sectors like oil, energy and agriculture. Steel, petroleum, chemical industries depend on electronics for daily processes and functions. Even hospitals in the health-care industry rely heavily on electronics to perform routine tests on patients. Safety measures in transportation, industries and homes also depend on electronics. An electronic engineer can find a job in Consumer electronics manufacturing organization , Telecommunication & IT industries, Health care equipment manufacturiContinue Reading There is bound to be huge demand for competent engineers in electronic industry to cope this demand in technology. The engineers would be involved in sustaining cutting edge technology to stay ahead in competition. Electronics have a major role to play in virtually every industry. They increase productivity in sectors like oil, energy and agriculture. Steel, petroleum, chemical industries depend on electronics for daily processes and functions. Even hospitals in the health-care industry rely heavily on electronics to perform routine tests on patients. Safety measures in transportation, industries and homes also depend on electronics. An electronic engineer can find a job in Consumer electronics manufacturing organization , Telecommunication & IT industries, Health care equipment manufacturiContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:39:36.691Z"),
    "question" : "What are the career opportunities after studying electronics engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d7b0c817f0398fae655"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-engineering-from-a-Tier-3-college-a-waste-of-time?-",
    "answer" : "The question is, Is engineering from a Tier 3 college a waste of time? And the answer is, Hell No! In fact in my humble opinion, this is actually a good use of time. I am going to explain why. I am assuming by Tier 3 colleges, you mean non-IIT, non-NIT colleges. Consider two guys called Apple and Android. Apple is a graduate from some IIT/NIT. He has spent most years of his life away from his family starting from boarding school to coaching centers to College. He is from a small district of Tamilnadu but studied engineering in North India. He hated the food at mess but then nothing could be done about that. He has a terrible social life and needles to say, no girlfriend. Android didn't waste time preparing for those overhyped entrance exams and joins the nearest engineering college he could fin Continue Reading The question is, Is engineering from a Tier 3 college a waste of time? And the answer is, Hell No! In fact in my humble opinion, this is actually a good use of time. I am going to explain why. I am assuming by Tier 3 colleges, you mean non-IIT, non-NIT colleges. Consider two guys called Apple and Android. Apple is a graduate from some IIT/NIT. He has spent most years of his life away from his family starting from boarding school to coaching centers to College. He is from a small district of Tamilnadu but studied engineering in North India. He hated the food at mess but then nothing could be done about that. He has a terrible social life and needles to say, no girlfriend. Android didn't waste time preparing for those overhyped entrance exams and joins the nearest engineering college he could fin Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:39:55.746Z"),
    "question" : "Is engineering from a Tier 3 college a waste of time? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d8c0c817f0398fae6c8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-start-my-career-in-software-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Nicu Popa The most obvious answer is to get a higher education degree in the field. There are advantages to this: It’s the easiest way to get a job afterwards for someone without actual experience because it provides the highest guarantee for a company that you actual know something.It provides basic principles in the domain and over a very broad area: from transistors and logic gates to hardware architecture, operating system, programming languages, software design, AI etc. This way you can choose which area is of actual interest to you, and pursue a career in that domain.There are trained individuals that will answer your question.There are other passionate individuals among colleagues with whom you can share ideas and whom you’ll have as contacts after graduation.Disadvantages: You’ll have to learn Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:40:12.910Z"),
    "question" : "How should I start my career in software engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369d9d0c817f0398fae6eb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-alternate-careers-for-a-software-engineer-in-India?-",
    "answer" : "There are plenty of questions already here on Quora, so I am just repurposing one of my older answers. It is best if you jump out of a “software engineer” career, earlier on, say 1–2 years into the job. Else you will be trapped by things like marriage, an apartment on EMI in an upcoming location in Bangalore that was mostly built on a lake, kids, a car, the entire Middle class - Indian dream. There is very little “ software engineering” happening in Indian IT firms anyways. You may hate me for speaking the truth, but I am calling a spade a spade. Production support and Excel sheet updation, or even using 2/3 screens of SAP do not make you a “ software engineer “ anyways. Like most cases, if your job can be done by someone who has passed 12th, sooner or later, they will find someone cheaper, m Continue Reading There are plenty of questions already here on Quora, so I am just repurposing one of my older answers. It is best if you jump out of a “software engineer” career, earlier on, say 1–2 years into the job. Else you will be trapped by things like marriage, an apartment on EMI in an upcoming location in Bangalore that was mostly built on a lake, kids, a car, the entire Middle class - Indian dream. There is very little “ software engineering” happening in Indian IT firms anyways. You may hate me for speaking the truth, but I am calling a spade a spade. Production support and Excel sheet updation, or even using 2/3 screens of SAP do not make you a “ software engineer “ anyways. Like most cases, if your job can be done by someone who has passed 12th, sooner or later, they will find someone cheaper, m Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:40:29.992Z"),
    "question" : "What are some alternate careers for a software engineer in India? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369db10c817f0398fae715"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-good-to-work-in-IT-companies-after-studying-mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "I am mechanical engineer and now I am working in IT industry as software tester with starting salary ₹18000 per month (which is double than salary in mechanical industry). Considering market value of mechanical engineer, jobs availability and number of engineers passing out every year answer is 'Yes'. I tried to get job for ond and half year. What they offered me was job of machine operator or technician ( it means job of ITI or Diploma holder). It will be a big set back in engineering career to accept such offers. My friend is persuing MTech from VIT Vellore. They told him to enter in research after PG because there are no jobs for mechanical. Half of the engineers passing out per year are mechanical, so comparatively in India job availability is less. Also most of the mechanical industries  Continue Reading I am mechanical engineer and now I am working in IT industry as software tester with starting salary ₹18000 per month (which is double than salary in mechanical industry). Considering market value of mechanical engineer, jobs availability and number of engineers passing out every year answer is 'Yes'. I tried to get job for ond and half year. What they offered me was job of machine operator or technician ( it means job of ITI or Diploma holder). It will be a big set back in engineering career to accept such offers. My friend is persuing MTech from VIT Vellore. They told him to enter in research after PG because there are no jobs for mechanical. Half of the engineers passing out per year are mechanical, so comparatively in India job availability is less. Also most of the mechanical industries  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:40:49.424Z"),
    "question" : "Is it good to work in IT companies after studying mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369dc70c817f0398fae798"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-40-too-late-to-start-a-career-in-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Let me start with the way I found this question. I am about to graduate with a degree in electrical engineering. Lets just say I’ll just be turning 40 and looking for an entry level position, and currently getting discouraged, which is how I found this post. I have been able to get internships, but not with ease. It still takes many iterations of my resume to find the right recipe that gets their attention. Recently I have been in the final round of interviews for a full time job, but the jobs have been given to another candidate. I’ve received many polite rejection letters so far. Don’t let the engineering hype fool you, it’s still tough out there even with a high gpa, great resume, and your new “high-paying” tech degree. I don’t think it’s impossible, just takes persistence. Here’s my 2  Continue Reading Let me start with the way I found this question. I am about to graduate with a degree in electrical engineering. Lets just say I’ll just be turning 40 and looking for an entry level position, and currently getting discouraged, which is how I found this post. I have been able to get internships, but not with ease. It still takes many iterations of my resume to find the right recipe that gets their attention. Recently I have been in the final round of interviews for a full time job, but the jobs have been given to another candidate. I’ve received many polite rejection letters so far. Don’t let the engineering hype fool you, it’s still tough out there even with a high gpa, great resume, and your new “high-paying” tech degree. I don’t think it’s impossible, just takes persistence. Here’s my 2  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:41:11.971Z"),
    "question" : "Is 40 too late to start a career in engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369e500c817f0398fae951"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-good-is-Epic-Systems-for-starting-a-career-as-a-software-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Vivek Prakash It's awesome. It's so good that it will blow your mind! Literally. Join Epic in whatever way possible. You should, in fact, beg them to hire you. Now, you write online tests, you appear in rigorous interviews and somehow you manage to be at your best in all of them. Then after you get selected among your friends who didn't get selected (you are already feeling proud about that!) and you start dreaming of your long wished American Dream which is soon going to be fulfilled, you fly off to join Epic Systems. A few days have passed living your American Dream. You have got a good cubicle in office from where you can hear the birds chirping, see the leaves rustling in the wind and watch the azure cloudless sky on a bright spring day. And it hits you. You realize that you don't need anything else. Y Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:43:28.544Z"),
    "question" : "How good is Epic Systems for starting a career as a software engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369e650c817f0398fae97d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Options-for-career-after-Mechanical-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Note: Plz don’t give any credit to me for this answer , as I have copied this text from a website , the website link is given below … You can choose the mechanical engineering, once you have completed your secondary or Sr. secondary examination. The academic criterion of Mechanical engineering is divided into three courses/programmes as follows: Diploma courses leading to the polytechnic diploma of 3 years duration.UG courses leading to the B.Tech (Bachelor of Technology) degree of 4 years duration.PG courses leading to the M.Tech (Master of Technology) degree of 2 years duration.Beside these, it is one of the broad research fields leading to the PhD (Doctor of Philosophy) degree. After the completion of 10th standard, you are only eligible to enter the diploma courses. Once you have done the  Continue Reading Note: Plz don’t give any credit to me for this answer , as I have copied this text from a website , the website link is given below … You can choose the mechanical engineering, once you have completed your secondary or Sr. secondary examination. The academic criterion of Mechanical engineering is divided into three courses/programmes as follows: Diploma courses leading to the polytechnic diploma of 3 years duration.UG courses leading to the B.Tech (Bachelor of Technology) degree of 4 years duration.PG courses leading to the M.Tech (Master of Technology) degree of 2 years duration.Beside these, it is one of the broad research fields leading to the PhD (Doctor of Philosophy) degree. After the completion of 10th standard, you are only eligible to enter the diploma courses. Once you have done the  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:43:49.930Z"),
    "question" : "Options for career after Mechanical engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369e7a0c817f0398fae9fd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-sales-a-good-career-after-engineering?-",
    "answer" : "Sales is always a great career option, technical understanding is icing on the cake. You can decide to start working in sales within your core sector to make it easy as you’d already have technical understanding. Not an engineer by qualification, but it worked out well for me. As a Draughtsman Mechanical when I first started selling recruiting services within the technical and construction market, I could relate to the jargons used by my prospects which created a comfort level for them to have a free flow conversation without having to explain me a whole lot. However, it is entirely up to the person to decide if this is something they want to trial or purse as a career. Do a thorough SWOT (Strength, Weakness, Opportunities, Threats) analysis and comparison between both your core and sales in l Continue Reading Sales is always a great career option, technical understanding is icing on the cake. You can decide to start working in sales within your core sector to make it easy as you’d already have technical understanding. Not an engineer by qualification, but it worked out well for me. As a Draughtsman Mechanical when I first started selling recruiting services within the technical and construction market, I could relate to the jargons used by my prospects which created a comfort level for them to have a free flow conversation without having to explain me a whole lot. However, it is entirely up to the person to decide if this is something they want to trial or purse as a career. Do a thorough SWOT (Strength, Weakness, Opportunities, Threats) analysis and comparison between both your core and sales in l Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:44:10.953Z"),
    "question" : "Is sales a good career after engineering? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369ea80c817f0398faea5d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-good-career-objective-for-a-mechanical-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Maxine Cole 9",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:44:56.968Z"),
    "question" : "What is a good career objective for a mechanical engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369f040c817f0398faebb7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-field-in-engineering-has-a-better-scope-for-the-future?-",
    "answer" : "Here are the courses described for you that will help you to decide your future course of action. Computer Science Engineering With the advancement of the IT industry, the demand for skilled software engineers and it professionals are at its peak. This is the engineering course which covers topics like programming languages, software knowledge, designing the programs, coding, project management and a lot more. A number of national as well as multinational companies offer amazing job opportunities to the computer science engineering graduates in India as well as in the foreign countries. To be eligible the student should have good aggregate marks in his higher secondary exam as well as high ranking in any of the state or National level Engineering entrance exams. Starting salary The starting salar Continue Reading Here are the courses described for you that will help you to decide your future course of action. Computer Science Engineering With the advancement of the IT industry, the demand for skilled software engineers and it professionals are at its peak. This is the engineering course which covers topics like programming languages, software knowledge, designing the programs, coding, project management and a lot more. A number of national as well as multinational companies offer amazing job opportunities to the computer science engineering graduates in India as well as in the foreign countries. To be eligible the student should have good aggregate marks in his higher secondary exam as well as high ranking in any of the state or National level Engineering entrance exams. Starting salary The starting salar Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:46:28.462Z"),
    "question" : "Which field in engineering has a better scope for the future? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60369f140c817f0398faebd8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-scope-for-a-telecommunication-engineer?-",
    "answer" : "Mithilesh Padhen The career prospects for Telecom engineers are increasing rapidly both in India and abroad because of the boom in this industry. Telecommunication Engineers are concerned with establishing communication by means of telephones, telegraphs, radar, radio, tele printers etc. Their work deals with designing, manufacturing, operating, maintaining, installing and troubleshooting of telecom devices. Telephone industry, computer industry, microwave radio systems, satellite communications, earth stations using satellite dishes, cellular phone industry, fiber optics communication systems etc. are some of the areas which provide job opportunities to the Telecommunication Engineers. Plenty of job opportunities are available for graduates in the telephone industry. They could be employed as engineers/ te Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T18:46:44.866Z"),
    "question" : "What is the scope for a telecommunication engineer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}